Guide to the Beverly Sufian Papers, 1989-2018 MS 812
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Beverly Sufian Papers
1989-2018
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Sufian, Beverly
MS 812
1.25 Linear Feet 3 boxes
Three boxes of adminstrative and event materials, newsletters and news clippings, and general organizational materials document some of the activities of the National Council of Jewish Women - Greater Houston Section from 1989 to 2018.
Biographical / Historical
The National Council of Jewish Women (NCJW) was founded in 1893 and is the oldest Jewish women's grassroots organization in the country. The mission of NCJW is to improve the lives of the most vulnerable women, children, and families in the United States and Israel. The organization responds to the most pressing challenges facing not only Jewish women, but all vulnerable women, children, and families. Some of their work includes protecting reproductive rights, child care, and passing civil rights legislation.
The organization has over 60 sections in 30 states, including the Greater Houston Section of which Beverly Sufian was president from 1985 to 1987.
Content Description
Three boxes of adminstrative and event materials, newsletters and news clippings, and general organizational materials document some of the activities of the National Council of Jewish Women - Greater Houston Section from 1989 to 2018.
Conditions Governing Access
The material is open for research.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Beverly Sufian in December 2021.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged on one series, with four sub-series, as follows:
Series I: National Council of Jewish Women: Subseries A: Adminstrative Materials; Subseries B: The Bulletin Newsletter / News Clippings; Subseries C: Event Materials; Subseries D: General
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life
Subjects (Persons)
Sufian, Beverly
Subjects (Corporations)
National Council of Jewish Women
- Series I: National Council of Jewish Women
  - Sub-series A: Administrative Materials
    - Policies and Procedures / Strategic Planning, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Board Materals, Chair Bonnie Herst, NCJW Greater Houston Section, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Aid to Victims of Domestic Violence (AVDA) Year-end Report, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Governing Board Meeting, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Board meeting materials and administrative paperwork, 2012-2014 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Restructuring Plan Draft, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Houston Independent School District HIPPY report, 2018-04 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - By-laws, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sub-series B: The Bulletin Newsletter / News Clippings
    - News clippings, 1989-2020 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - NCJW Bulletin, 1990-09-2004-06 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - NCJW Bulletin, 2004-09-2008-06 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - NCJW Bulletin, 2008-2011 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - National Journal, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sub-series C: Event Materials
    - Invitations and Program Announcements, 1990-2005 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Women's Intergenerational Seder, 1995-2017 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Women's Seder Haggadot, 1997-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Starlight Ball, 2005-12-03 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - NCJW Day on the Hill, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Invitations and Program Announcements, 2007-2021 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Make Someone Happy silent auction, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Shabbat Service, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Havdalah Service, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Sub-series D: General
    - National organization printed materials, 1999-2002 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Membership Directory, 2007-2008 (Box 3)
    - Houston section printed materials, 2009-2012 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Fundraising materials, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Informational handouts / position statements (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Organizing Institute and Network (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Flyers / Brochures, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Photocopied photographs, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - NCJW t-shirt, n.d. (Box 3)